
export const quizQuestions_1 = {
  questions: [
    {
      question: 'In ReactJS, what is the primary purpose of a functional component?',
      choices: ['To manage state', 'To render UI', 'To handle events', 'To define classes'],
      correctAnswer: 'To render UI',
    },
    {
      question: 'Which keyword is used to declare a functional component in React?',
      choices: ['function', 'class', 'component', 'const'],
      correctAnswer: 'function',
    },
    {
      question: 'How do you pass data to a child component in React?',
      choices: ['Through props', 'Using state', 'Direct method invocation', 'Global variables'],
      correctAnswer: 'Through props',
    },
    {
      question: 'Which of the following is true about functional components in React?',
      choices: [
        'They can have local state',
        'They cannot receive props',
        'They are always stateless',
        'They cannot be arrow functions',
      ],
      correctAnswer: 'They can have local state',
    },
    {
      question: 'In a functional component, where should you perform side effects such as data fetching?',
      choices: ['In the render method', 'In the constructor', 'In a separate function', 'In the useEffect hook'],
      correctAnswer: 'In the useEffect hook',
    },
    {
      question: 'What is the purpose of the "key" prop in React?',
      choices: ['To uniquely identify elements in a list', 'To define CSS styles', 'To set component state', 'To declare component props'],
      correctAnswer: 'To uniquely identify elements in a list',
    },
    {
      question: 'Which of the following is a valid way to define PropTypes for a functional component?',
      choices: ['propTypes property within the component', 'Using the prop-types library', 'Both A and B', 'None of the above'],
      correctAnswer: 'Both A and B',
    },
    {
      question: 'What is the significance of the "children" prop in React?',
      choices: ['It contains child components', 'It represents the text content between the opening and closing tags', 'It is used for styling', 'It is not a valid prop'],
      correctAnswer: 'It represents the text content between the opening and closing tags',
    },
    {
      question: 'How can you conditionally render content in a React component?',
      choices: ['Using the if-else statement', 'By directly manipulating the DOM', 'Using the ternary operator', 'Conditionally rendering is not possible in React'],
      correctAnswer: 'Using the ternary operator',
    },
    {
      question: 'What is the purpose of the React Fragment?',
      choices: ['To create fragments of UI', 'To group multiple elements without adding extra nodes to the DOM', 'To define the structure of the component', 'To encapsulate state'],
      correctAnswer: 'To group multiple elements without adding extra nodes to the DOM',
    },
  ],
}